A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Educational Interests, Series G FA316
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Colleges
  - Colleges - Connecticut College, 1958-1961 (Box 63, Folder 441A)
  - Colleges - Cornell University, 1901-1920 (Box 63, Folder 442)
    John D. Rockefeller's 1901 conditional gift of $250,000 for physics building; 1917 pledge for chemistry building lapsed when conditions not fulfilled. Other miscellaneous contributions. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1917 address at Cornell: "The Personal Relation in Industry." Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, George F. Baker, W. I. Myers, Edmund E. Day.
  - Colleges - Cornell University, 1920-1961 (Box 63, Folder 443)
  - Colleges - Cornell University, 1951-1955 (Box 63, Folder 443A)
  - Colleges - Cornell University - Cornell University Medical School, 1901-1961 (Box 63, Folder 444)
    Declinations of appeals.
  - Colleges - Cornell University - Dorado Beach Scholarship, 1959-1962 (Box 63, Folder 445)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller creates scholarship fund for Puerto Ricans at Cornell studying hotel administration.
  - Colleges - Cumberland University, 1930-1945 (Box 63, Folder 446)
    Appeals for aid declined until 1944 John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of $500 went towards memorial library for Cordell Hull. Correspondents include Cordell Hull, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson.
  - Colleges - Dartmouth College
    Nelson A. Rockefeller's admission. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s personal friendship with President E. M. Hopkins. Offer of honorary degree to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Nelson A. Rockefeller's college career. Appeals for special gifts. President J. S. Dickey. Tribute to E. M. Hopkins. Nelson A. Rockefeller contributions; Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include E. M. Hopkins, J. S. Dickey, Charles O. Heydt, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    - 1958 (Box 64, Folder 447)
    - 1920-1928 (Box 64, Folder 448)
    - 1929-1943 (Box 64, Folder 0448A)
    - 1945-1961 (Box 64, Folder 0448B)
    - 1953-1960 (Box 64, Folder 0448C)
  - Colleges - Dartmouth College - Dartmouth Christian Association, 1926-1930 (Box 64, Folder 449)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s annual $250 gift.
  - Colleges - Dartmouth College - Rupert Brooke Collection, 1931 (Box 64, Folder 450)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. at Nelson A. Rockefeller's request paid one half the cost of the collection.
  - Colleges - Dartmouth College - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Address, June 1930 (Box 64, Folder 451)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. addressed Senior meeting of Nelson A. Rockefeller's class on honor and duty and son's devotion to father.
  - Colleges - Dartmouth College - Gift, February 25, 1928, 1927-1943 (Box 64, Folder 452)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives $750,000 for endowment of Honors course.
  - Colleges - Dartmouth College - Research in Optics Pledge, 1929-1934 (Box 64, Folder 453)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. after eye treatment gave research center $80,000 over 5 years.
  - Colleges - Dartmouth College - Eye Institute, 1941-1948 (Box 64, Folder 454)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions.
  - Colleges - Dartmouth College - 1950 Pledge, 1949-1954 (Box 64, Folder 455)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives $250,000 as tribute to E. M. Hopkins.
  - Colleges - Dartmouth College - 1956 Pledge, 1956-1959 (Box 64, Folder 456)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives $1,000,000 towards building of campus cultural center.
  - Colleges - Denison University, 1890-1906 (Box 64, Folder 457)
    John D. Rockefeller contributions to school before 1905, when General Education Board assumed task. 1927 requests for aid declined by Rockefellers and General Education Board. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Frederick T. Gates, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Colleges - Denison University, 1911-1958 (Box 64, Folder 0457A)
  - Colleges - Fisk University, 1925-1928 (Box 65, Folder 458)
    Appeal made to better racial understanding by W. H. Baldwin, 1925; in 1926 John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made $60,000 conditional gift, which lapsed. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. remained interested in Fisk, urging General Education Board aid for it. Friendly personal relations with President T. E. Jones. No gifts in 1930s or 1940s though interest high. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, T. B. Appleget, T. E. Jones.
  - Colleges - Fisk University, 1928-1953 (Box 65, Folder 459)
  - Colleges - Fisk University - Commencement Address, June 6, 1928, 1927-1928 (Box 65, Folder 460)
    Preparations for address and for short talk before Nashville Chamber of Commerce. Newspaper reports on speech and on short address. Comments on speeches.
  - Colleges - Fisk University - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Address, May 1941, 1941-1943 (Box 65, Folder 461)
    Celebration of Fisk's 75th Anniversary; attended by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and John D. Rockefeller 3rd; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. refused honorary degree, but gave speech presenting his Credo. Permission to print remarks to publicize Fisk fund drive. Comments on speech; manuscript and printed copies of it.
  - Colleges - Fisk University - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Correspondence, 1930-1941 (Box 65, Folder 462)
    Invitations, reports on music education at Fisk; aid to individual students.
  - Colleges - Fisk University - Mrs. Myers and Jubilee Singers, 1927-1953 (Box 65, Folder 463)
    Fisk choir performed privately for Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in their New York home. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made special contributions to various expenses of the choir. Gifts by Mary French Rockefeller to Mrs. Meyers. Singers were not related to the University in later years. John D. Rockefeller 3rd contribution to group for European tour in 1956. Declinations of appeals from Mrs. Meyers. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mary French Rockefeller, Robert W. Gumbel, Mrs. James Meyers, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - Fisk University - Mrs. Myers and Jubilee Singers, 1953-1960 (Box 65, Folder 464)
  - Colleges - Fordham University, 1940-1960 (Box 65, Folder 465)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller was given honorary Doctor of Law degree in 1941 in abstentia. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. attended; Laurance S. Rockefeller received degree for Nelson A. Rockefeller. Laurance S. Rockefeller contribution for special conference on peace. David Rockefeller anonymous contribution in 1955 to aid Lincoln Center campus. John D. Rockefeller 3rd anonymous contribution; Nelson A. Rockefeller anonymous contribution, 1959. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, L. J. McGinley, Robert I. Gannon.
  - Colleges - Fordham University, 1955 (Box 65, Folder 0465A)
  - Colleges - George Peabody College for Teachers, 1903-1958 (Box 65, Folder 466)
    General Education Board and Rockefeller contributions to College; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest in it. John D. Rockefeller 3rd declines trusteeship, 1948. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, George Peabody, Dr. Henry Hill.
  - Colleges - German Presbyterian Theological School of the Northwest, Dubuque, Iowa, 1909-1920 (Box 66, Folder 467)
    Request to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. referred to General Education Board. President Steffens very persistent, but was consistently refused. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., C. M. Steffens, W. Rose, Willard S. Richardson.
  - Colleges - Gordon College of Theology and Missions, 1930-1957 (Box 66, Folder 468)
    John D. Rockefeller makes small contributions to Baptist school in Boston, 1930-1936. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. not interested. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, William Sheppard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dana S. Creel.
  - Colleges - Hampton Institute, 1917-1950 (Box 66, Folder 469)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. visit to Hampton, 1926; interest in school's music program. Satisfaction with education there. Declined requests for aid. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Arthur Howe, James E. Gregg, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - Hampton Institute - Choir Tour, 1929-1931 (Box 66, Folder 0469A)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. paid half the cost of the tour.
  - Colleges - Hampton Institute - Ogden Memorial, 1915-1917 (Box 66, Folder 0469B)
    John D. Rockefeller gave $10,000 towards Memorial Hall.
  - Colleges - Hampton Institute - Scholarship Fund, 1899-1901, 1932 (Box 66, Folder 0469C)
    Annual gifts, $280 to $700 annually for student aid.
  - Colleges - Hampton Institute - Contributions, 1902-1940 (Box 66, Folder 469)
    Special small gifts by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Colleges - Hampton Institute - Campaign - Hampton-Tuskegee, 1925, 1925-1940 (Box 66, Folder 470)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes $1,000,000 towards $8,000,000 goal of both schools. Mr. Eastman gave $3,000,000. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. also acted as solicitor among some of his friends. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Woods, Anson P. Stokes.
  - Colleges - Harding College, 1938-1956 (Box 66, Folder 471)
    Conservative Arkansas school dedicated to free economy. Militant president made steady appeals for family funds, all declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
  - Colleges - Hartford Seminary Foundation / Hartford Theological Seminary, 1912-1927 (Box 66, Folder 472)
    Foundation to train Bible teachers, not ministers. Letter by Frederick T. Gates on need to educate the common man; Frederick T. Gates urges personal donation to liberal colleges. Willard S. Richardson and Raymond B. Fosdick disagree widely on propriety of gift to Foundation in 1924. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. ultimately decided to give $250,000. Offered $300,000 conditionally in 1929 - only $23,000 paid. Requests declined after 1939. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Raymond B. Fosdick, Frederick T. Gates. Dr. E. K. Mitchell.
  - Colleges - Hartford Seminary Foundation / Hartford Theological Seminary, 1927-1929 (Box 66, Folder 473)
  - Colleges - Hartford Seminary Foundation / Hartford Theological Seminary, 1930-1953 (Box 66, Folder 474)
  - Colleges - Harvard University
    John D. Rockefeller's $1,000,000 conditional gift to Harvard Medical School, 1902; discussion of school's role in medical research; printed copy of Starr J. Murphy's report. 1918 appeal for aid to School of Education referred to General Education Board. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's projects for Japanese-American intellectuals exchange program and Distinguished Service Fellowship program, 1951-1952; Conant not interested, so John D. Rockefeller 3rd took them to Columbia and Princeton. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declines honorary degree, 1957. The Program for Harvard College fund campaign - contributions by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (at David Rockefeller's request), $50,000; Nelson A. Rockefeller, $51,000; David Rockefeller, $1,500,000. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declines John D. Rockefeller 3rd's 1959 recommendation of King of Thailand for honorary degree. Nelson A. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller 3rd's parents contributions. Correspondents include E. O. Reischauer, Nathan Pusey, R. Keith Kane, Sebastian S. Kresge, Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    - 1900-1904 (Box 67, Folder 475)
    - 1907-1927 (Box 67, Folder 0475A)
    - 1928-1946 (Box 67, Folder 0475B)
    - 1946 (Box 67, Folder 0475C)
    - 1947-1955 (Box 67, Folder 476)
    - 1955-1961 (Box 67, Folder 0476A)
    - 1955-1961 (Box 67, Folder 476B)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Fogg Museum - China Expedition, 1922-1928 (Box 67, Folder 477)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives $2500 toward expenses.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Fogg Museum - 1924 Gift, 1924-1926 (Box 67, Folder 478)
    In honor of Charles Eliot's 90th birthday, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $500,000 for expansion.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Dinner at Williamsburg, 1941 (Box 67, Folder 479)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller hostess for Harvard Overseers at Raleigh Tavern.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - W. L. Mackenzie King Memorial, 1951-1961 (Box 67, Folder 480)
    David Rockefeller pledges matching gift, 1961. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. considers contributing towards memorial.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - W. L. Mackenzie King Memorial, 1961 (Box 67, Folder 0480A)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Harvard Glee Club, 1960-1961 (Box 67, Folder 481)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Francis W. Peabody Memorial Fund, 1929 (Box 67, Folder 482)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $25,000 for intern fellowships.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Friends of Art and Music at Harvard, 1929-1960 (Box 67, Folder 483)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller a regular contributor; David Rockefeller made several gifts. Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Persian Miniatures sent to Fogg Museum, 1960.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Friends of Art and Music at Harvard, 1949-1955 (Box 67, Folder 0483A)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Arnold Arboretum, 1922-1950 (Box 68, Folder 484)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined to contribute until 1949; then he gave $1,000 annually through Mrs. Max Ferrand. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Harvard Club of New York City and Boston, 1941-1962 (Box 68, Folder 485)
    David Rockefeller's contributions to New York City scholarship fund. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, Richard Dana.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Harvard Divinity School
    James Conant asked John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to aid school; Rockefeller office study of school's problems. David Rockefeller's contribution of $100,000. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gift of $1,000,000 in 1953. Later appeals declined. Sealantic Fund made gifts. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Jones, Dana S. Creel, N. M. Pusey, James B. Conant, David Rockefeller.
    - 1944-1954 (Box 68, Folder 486)
    - 1944-1954 (Box 68, Folder 0486A)
    - 1954-1958 (Box 68, Folder 487)
    - 1954-1958 (Box 68, Folder 0487A)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Harvard Divinity School - 1953 Gift, 1952-1954 (Box 68, Folder 488)
    Letters of commendation to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Institute for Solar Research, 1952-1961 (Box 68, Folder 489)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller gives $20,000 towards Colorado research center. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, W. O. Roberts, Harper Woodward.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Professor Lake's Excavations, 1924-1937 (Box 68, Folder 490)
    Professor Lakes engaged in photographic reproductions of carvings and Biblical manuscripts. Through Arthur Woods, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made several small contributions to journeys to Mt. Athos, Mt. Sinai, and Sumaria. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Woods, Raymond B. Fosdick, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Law School, 1927-1961 (Box 68, Folder 491)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1927 $100,000 conditional gift for research in law; 1928 gift for research in legal codification. Laurance S. Rockefeller's 1949 nonrecurring gift. Laurance S. Rockefeller's nonrecurring 1959 gift. John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller contribution to Hinckley Loan and Scholarship Fund. Correspondents include Erwin Griswold, Raymond B. Fosdick, Arthur W. Packard, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Law School, 1948-1961 (Box 68, Folder 0491A)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Medical School, 1950-1960 (Box 68, Folder 492)
    Declinations of various appeals and invitations. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Medical School, 1950-1960 (Box 68, Folder 0492A)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - School of Business
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s friendship with Dean David; his gift of $5,000,000 in 1949. David Rockefeller's interest in school; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's interest in Far East Business conferences. Laurance S. Rockefeller on Aviation Advisory Committee. Correspondents include Donald K. David, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    - 1947-1960 (Box 69, Folder 493)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 69, Folder 0493A)
    - 1949-1960 (Box 69, Folder 494)
    - 1951-1954 (Box 69, Folder 0494A)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - School of Business - 1949 Gift
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledges $5,000,000 through Dean David; letters of appreciation for gift. Construction of Aldrich Hall; dedication; address by Winthrop W. Aldrich. Winthrop Aldrich's comments on Nelson W. Aldrich and John D. Rockefeller. Correspondents include Donald K. David, Winthrop Aldrich, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    - 1948-1950 (Box 69, Folder 495)
    - 1951-1957 (Box 69, Folder 496)
    - 1953-1957 (Box 69, Folder 0496A)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - School of Public Health, 1947-1960 (Box 69, Folder 497)
    General Simmons 1952 statement on "Contribution of Philanthropic Foundations to Medicine and Public Health." Laurance S. Rockefeller's interest in research on aviation health and safety. Marked copy of Dr. Snyder's 1959 Riverside Lecture on Ethics and Public Health. Re Dr. Hamlin. Declinations of appeals. Correspondents include Ross McFarland, Dr. John C. Snyder, Dr. Robert Hamlin, Gen. J. Simmons, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - State Department Training Program, 1952-1953 (Box 69, Folder 498)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd interested in setting up program at Harvard Graduate School of Public Administration in conjunction with Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) for special training of foreign service information personnel. McLean's draft outlines and memos on his negotiations with State Department and University personnel. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's contribution covering program's cost. Then State Department backed out for budgetary reasons, and project and grant dropped. Correspondents include D. H. McLean, Robert Freeman, Edward Mason, Paul Herzog, Theodore G. Streibert, John Foster Dulles, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - State Department Training Program, 1953-1956 (Box 69, Folder 499)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Harvard-Yenching Institute
    Well-endowed Institute administers fund to strengthen higher education in Asia and establish Far Eastern Center at Harvard. John D. Rockefeller 3rd became a trustee, 1955; 1956-1957 reappraisal of Institute's objectives. Various marked copies of draft agendas and reports. 1961 financial statement and minutes. Copy of original and revised by-laws. Correspondents include F. Gregg Bemis, Edward Reischauer, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    - 1955 (Box 70, Folder 500)
    - 1956 (Box 70, Folder 501)
    - 1957-1959 (Box 70, Folder 502)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 70, Folder 503)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller, 1942-1949 (Box 71, Folder 504)
    David Rockefeller service on Visiting Committee, Fund Council; small contributions to special projects. David Rockefeller was Grand Marshall in 1961 commencement; was an Overseer of University. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard, Richard Dana.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller, 1951-1960 (Box 71, Folder 0504A)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller, 1961-1963 (Box 71, Folder 0504B)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller - Contributions, 1946-1958 (Box 71, Folder 505)
    David Rockefeller contributions to Alumni Fund, Law School, scholarship fund, towards furnishings of Dana-Palmer House, Undergraduate library, Memorial Window at Southwork Cathedral; towards publication of volume by Schumpeter. Many other small contributions to special projects. 1955-1957 gift of $1,000,000 for Harvard College; $500,000 gift to endow Abby Aldrich Rockefeller professorship in Oriental Art, 1957. Gift of two portraits, 1959; support for student magazine of political opinions. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Richard Dana, James B. Conant.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller - Contributions, 1959-1960 (Box 71, Folder 0505A)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller - Contributions, 1961 (Box 71, Folder 0505B)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller - Contributions - Harvard University Library, 1951-1953 (Box 71, Folder 506)
    David Rockefeller contribution towards publication of studies by ex-communists.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller - Contributions - Pledge, 1959, 1959-1961 (Box 71, Folder 507)
    $1,000,000 for Harvard College.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller - Harvard Foundation for Advanced Study and Research, 1948-1953 (Box 71, Folder 508)
    David Rockefeller declines invitation to join executive committee; contributes from $1000 to $5000 annually, 1950-1961. Lists of contributors; 1961 copies of Foundation Newsletters. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Dexter Perkins, Robert Bates, Gordon Huggins.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller - Harvard Foundation for Advanced Study and Research, 1954-1958 (Box 71, Folder 0508A)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller - Harvard Foundation for Advanced Study and Research, 1959-1961 (Box 71, Folder 0508B)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller - Salzburg Seminar, 1947-1949 (Box 72, Folder 509)
    David Rockefeller's annual contributions to Seminar on American civilization held in Austria. 1958 large gift toward purchase of Castle for Seminar. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Dexter Perkins, Robert Bates, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - David Rockefeller - Salzburg Seminar, 1950-1960 (Box 72, Folder 0509A)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - George D. O'Neill, 1960-1961 (Box 72, Folder 510)
  - Colleges - Harvard University - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1943-1961 (Box 72, Folder 511)
    Small contribution to Rhinelander Foundation, 1947; declinations. Correspondents include Rev. Frederic B. Kellogg, Arthur W. Packard, H. A. Kissinger.
  - Colleges - Harvard University - John D. Rockefeller IV, 1961 (Box 72, Folder 512)
  - Colleges - Haverford College, 1932-1959 (Box 72, Folder 513)
    Declinations; miscellaneous correspondence. Correspondents include Gilbert White, Hugh Borton, Edgar B. Young, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - Haverford College - Rufus M. Jones Fund, 1948-1951 (Box 72, Folder 0513A)
    Requests for contribution to memorial fund declined, since John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and David Rockefeller had contributed to similar fund set up at Bryn Mawr. John D. Rockefeller 3rd declined.
  - Colleges - Hebrew Union College - Jewish Institute of Religion, 1958-1961 (Box 72, Folder 514)
    Declinations of appeals. John D. Rockefeller 3rd received honorary degree, 1961. Correspondents include Nelson Glueck, Mrs. Sulzburger, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - Hebrew Union College - Jewish Institute of Religion - Frank Weil Institute of Advanced Studies in Religion and the Humanities, 1958-1960 (Box 72, Folder 0514A)
    Contributions of $10,000 each by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and John D. Rockefeller 3rd in 1958. Both decline to serve on committee. Correspondents include R. C. Bates, Howard Mumford Jones, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Colleges - Homeopathic Colleges, 1911-1928 (Box 72, Folder 515)
    Contributing opposed by Frederick T. Gates and Starr J. Murphy; no contributions made. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, H. W. Bigger.